export const quizData = {
  title: 'General Knowledge Quiz',
  description: 'Test your knowledge with these general knowledge questions!',
  questions: [
    { 
      question: '1. …………… state that if the temperature of three bodies after separation remains the same, they are said to be in thermodynamic equilibrium ',
      options: ['Equilibrium law', 'Kelvin law', 'Thermodynamic law', 'Zeroth law'],
      answer: 'Zeroth law'
    },
    { 
      question: '2. According to the kinetic theory, molecules of different gases at the same temperature always have the same ………..',
      options: ['Average density', 'Volume', 'Pressure ', 'Average kinetic energy'],
      answer: 'Average kinetic energy'
    },
    { 
      question: '3. The parameter that determines the direction of heat flow when two bodies are in contact',
      options: ['Heat', 'Boiling point', 'Saturated vapor pressure', 'Latent heat'],
      answer: 'Saturated vapor pressure'
    },
    { 
      question: '4. Intermolecular force exists in solids since they are …………',
      options: ['Scattered', 'Loosely packed', 'Closely packed', 'Strong'],
      answer: 'Closely packed'
    },
    { 
      question: '5. The molecules of a solid are arranged in a repeated regular pattern known as',
      options: ['Array ', 'Lattice', 'Block', 'Patterns'],
      answer: 'Lattice'
    },
    { 
      question: '6. A cylinder contains oxygen at a temperature of 20°C and pressure of 15 atm in a volume of 100 L. A piston is lowered into the cylinder, decreasing the volume occupied by the gas to 80 L and raising the temperature to 25°C. Assuming oxygen behaves like an ideal gas under this condition, what is the pressure?',
      options: ['38.2 atm', '19.1 atm', '19.1 Pa'],
      answer: '19.1 atm'
    },
    { 
      question: '7. Pressure, volume, and temperature are known as ………. Properties of matter',
      options: ['Microscopic', 'Macroscopic', 'Physical', 'Mechanical'],
      answer: 'Macroscopic'
    },
    { 
      question: '8. The following are effects of heat except',
      options: ['It causes temporary madness', 'It causes thermal agitation in molecules', 'It causes no change in state', 'It causes boiling'],
      answer: 'It causes no change in state'
    },
    { 
      question: '9. The pressure of a constant volume gas thermometer is 1500 N/m² at 28°C. What will be the temperature of the gas when the pressure increases by 1/3 atm?',
      options: ['301 K', '401.3 K', ' 301°C', '401.3°C'],
      answer: '401.3 K'
    },
    { 
      question: '10. From Boyle\'s law, the relation is',
      options: ['PV=K', 'P=V/K ', 'V=PK', 'V=P/K'],
      answer: 'PV=K'
    },
    { 
      question: '11. Which of the following is true? If two gases under the same conditions have the same number of molecules then they must (i) have the same number of molecules (ii) occupy the same volume (iii) different number of molecules (iv) occupy different volume ',
      options: ['i only', 'i and ii', 'ii and iii ', 'iii and iv'],
      answer: 'i and ii'
    },
    { 
      question: '12. The molecules in a ________________ are scattered',
      options: ['Solid', 'Liquid', 'Gas', 'Plasma'],
      answer: 'Gas'
    },
    { 
      question: '13. The ratio of tensile stress to tensile strain is',
      options: ['Young modulus', 'Shear modulus', 'Modulus of rigidity', 'Tension modulus'],
      answer: 'Young modulus'
    },
    { 
      question: '14. The ability of a material to return to its original shape and size after the distorting force has been removed is',
      options: ['Plasticity', 'Elasticity', 'Resistivity', 'Ductility'],
      answer: 'Elasticity'
    },
    { 
      question: '15. A material 4m long and 2cm² in cross-section stretched 2mm when a mass of 20kg is placed at the lower end. find E Young modulus',
      options: ['19.6 * 10¹¹ N/m²', '1.96 * 10¹⁰ N/m²', '1.96 * 10¹¹ N/m²', '1.96 * 10⁻⁶ N/m²'],
      answer: '1.96 * 10¹⁰ N/m²'
    },
    { 
      question: '16. Energy can neither be created nor destroyed but can be converted from one form to another is inferred from. ',
      options: ['Zeroth law of thermodynamic ', 'First law of thermodynamic', 'Second law of thermodynamic', 'Third law of thermodynamics'],
      answer: 'First law of thermodynamic'
    },
    { 
      question: '17. At …………… a stretched material can still return to its original shape but it does not obey Hooke’s law ',
      options: ['Breaking point', 'Yield point', 'Elastic limit', 'Fracture point'],
      answer: 'Yield point'
    },
    { 
      question: '18. A wire of 2kg is attached to the end of a vertical wire of length 2m and diameter 2mm and the wire extend 1mm. calculate the tensile stress ',
      options: ['6.37 * 10⁶ N/m²', '6.37 * 10⁵ N/m²', '63.7 * 10⁶ N/m²', '10⁷ N/m²'],
      answer: '6.37 * 10⁶ N/m²'
    },
    { 
      question: '19. A wire of 2kg is attached to the end of a vertical wire of length 2m and diameter 2mm and the wire extend 1mm. calculate the tensile strain',
      options: ['0.0005mm', '0.00005mm', '0.0005', '0.00005'],
      answer: '0.0005'
    },
    { 
      question: '20. A steel rod of cross-sectional area 2cm² heated to 100°C and then prevented from contracting when it is cooled to 10°C. if the linear expansivity is 12 * 10⁻⁶ K⁻¹ and young modulus 2 * 10¹¹ N/m². Calculate the force of contraction',
      options: ['4.32 * 10⁴', '4.32 * 10⁵', '4.32 * 10⁶'],
      answer: '4.32 * 10⁴'
          }    
      ]   
  };